# **Jeyson Molina**

# Software developer. Systems and Software engineer.

Mobile: (+57) 3193893467 Email: jeyson.mco@gmail.com

Web: <a href="http://jeysonm.co/">http://jeysonm.co/</a>

Address: CLL 26 # 43-59 Apt. 1903. Bello, Antioquia - Colombia

### **PERSONAL SUMMARY**

An efficient, committed and hardworking software developer with 5+ years of experience in software development projects. I've been involved in different kinds of software projects like data processing, computer vision, standalone apps and Websites (both frontend and backend). I've been involved in all aspects of a software project, including software requirements and planning, development, testing and deploy. Programming is my job but is also my hobby being python my favorite programming language which I use everywhere.

I'm looking for a new challenge in the software development area, one where I can put my skills to use and further my experience.

### **AREAS OF EXPERTISE**

- Python
- Django
- REST
- HTML5
- CSS3
- Bootstrap 3
- Javascript ES5, ES6
- Jquery
- ReactJS
- Git
- MySQL, SQLite
- Testing (TDD)
- Agile development (Scrum)
- Linux

### **ACADEMIC QUALIFICATIONS**

2012. Systems and software engineer. National university of Colombia.

I graduated from the Systems and software engineering program of the National university of

Colombia, one of the top 3 universities in my country. This experience gave me the core concepts and initial experience to work in the software development area.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

# Python Software developer - Freelance. (2010-Present).

I worked as a freelance developer using Python based technologies to develop standalone applications and websites (back-end and front-end). I developed different kinds of websites like: corporate sites, dashboards, e-commerce, catalogs, etc. For websites I used Django + MySQL for the back-end and Bootstrap + CSS3 + Javascript (JQuery, ReactJS) for the front-end.

My development environment consisted in a Fedora workstation, gvim editor and several tools for the backe-end and front-end dev including: git, pip, virtualenv, npm, gulp, bash console, docker, virtualbox, etc.

On the other hand, I developed standalone apps for Windows systems using python and kivy for the GUI.

Finally, my job consisted not only on the programming part but also planning, designing and deploying the solutions.

#### **Duties:**

- Develop websites using Python, HTML5 and Javascript technologies (Django 1.6 to 1.9, MySQL, HTML5, Javascript ES5/ES6, Jquery, ReactJS, CSS3, etc.), both front-end and back-end.
- Deploy websites in Linux VPS machines using NGINX + UWSGI.
- Develop standalone applications using Python (kivy, tkinter, wxwidgets).

**Sample projects**: (Please check <a href="http://jeysonm.co/#sample-projects">http://jeysonm.co/#sample-projects</a> for a better presentation of these projects).

- "Jeyson Molina" website: Personal website (<a href="http://jeysonm.co">http://jeysonm.co</a>). Techs used (Django, HTML5, CSS3, ES6, ReactJS, JQuery, Bootstrap).
- "El Olimpico" website: E-commerce website. Demo: <a href="http://45.55.138.14:8900/">http://45.55.138.14:8900/</a> (not yet released). Techs used (Django, HTML5, CSS3, ES6, ReactJS, JQuery, RESTful API).
- "Agrotecnico" website: Product catalog website (<a href="http://www.agrotecnico.com.co">http://www.agrotecnico.com.co</a>), sample repository (<a href="https://bitbucket.org/jasoncol/agrotecnico/src">https://bitbucket.org/jasoncol/agrotecnico/src</a>). Techs used (Django,

HTML5, CSS3, ES5, JQuery).

- "Idearsas website": Corporate website (<a href="http://www.idearsas.com/">http://www.idearsas.com/</a>), repository (<a href="https://bitbucket.org/jasoncol/idear\_web/src">https://bitbucket.org/jasoncol/idear\_web/src</a>). Techs used (Django, HTML5, CSS3, ES5, JQuery, Booststrap 3 for responsive).
- "Pei reportes" website: Dashboard Website (<a href="http://45.55.138.14:8000/">http://45.55.138.14:8000/</a>) repository (I can provide sample code on request). Techs used (Django, HTML5, CSS3, ES5, JQuery, Booststrap 3, ChartJS, OLAP server, Ajax).
- "Pei Checklist" standalone application: Python kivy standalone app Executable (https://goo.gl/YSEOo6) Repository (https://bitbucket.org/jasoncol/pei\_checklist/src)
- "Joseuroboros" website: Corporate website (<a href="http://www.joseuroboros.ml/">http://www.joseuroboros.ml/</a>), repository (<a href="https://bitbucket.org/jasoncol/jauroboros/src">https://bitbucket.org/jasoncol/jauroboros/src</a>). Techs used (Django, HTML5, CSS3, JS6, Boostrap, ReactJS, JQuery).

# National university of Colombia.

Software developer. (2014-2014)

I developed a graphical user interface frontend and a fortran wrapper that integrated several fortran based programs. I also elaborated reports, presentations and proposed solutions for several parts of the project. Scrum methodology was used.

#### **Duties:**

- Develop a Java based (javafx) frontend for the project.
- Develop a Python based (django) web frontend for the project.
- Develop a C/C++ based wrapper to connect Java logic with Fortran logic.
- Elaborate reports, presentations.

# Links:

- Repository ( https://bitbucket.org/midf software/midf/src)

# ■ ITM. Metropolitan technological institute

Research assistant and software developer. (2013-2013)

I worked as a research assistant performing experiments in an optics laboratory and as a software developer creating embedded software for portable systems like Raspberry pi, Beaglebone, etc.

#### **Duties:**

- Elaborate reports and academic papers.
- Manipulate and operate specialized hardware for image acquisition.
- Develop Python scripts for data processing. (numpy, pandas, scikit, matplotlib).
- Develop Python scripts that can be run on embedded systems, interface with its hardware (GPIO inputs, outputs).

#### Links:

- Repository (<a href="https://goo.gl/EaWVcv">https://goo.gl/EaWVcv</a>)

# National university of Colombia.

# Research assistant and software developer. (2010-2013)

I worked as a research assistant performing experiments in the laboratory and writing academic papers in the computer vision and artificial intelligence field. I also developed several scripts and software to process data and to implement specialized algorithms from the research field.

#### **Duties:**

- Elaborate reports and academic papers.
- Manipulate and operate specialized hardware for image acquisition.
- Develop Python scripts for data processing. (numpy, pandas, scikit, matplotlib).
- Develop Python scripts for image processing. (opency, scikit-image).
- Labview software development.

### Links:

Repository (<u>https://bitbucket.org/jasoncol/image\_proc/src</u>)

## WebCreativa StudioWeB

PHP Software developer. (2008-2009)

I worked as a software developer creating websites from scratch using PHP, Javascript, CSS and HTML.

### **Duties:**

- Backend software development using PHP as scripting language and MySQL for database.
- Frontend software development using HTML5 + Javascript + CSS3.
- Software testing and deploy.

### **OPEN SOURCE AND PERSONAL PROJECTS:**

- Python Google speech wrappers:
  - https://github.com/jeysonmc/python-google-speech-scripts
- React like components for Brython:
  - https://github.com/jeysonmc/brython-components
- Kivy widget iconfonts: <a href="https://github.com/jeysonmc/garden.iconfonts">https://github.com/jeysonmc/garden.iconfonts</a>
- More: https://github.com/jeysonmc

#### **REFERENCES:**

**Camilo José Vargas Cortés.** (Systems and Software engineer. M.Sc Computer science) Researcher at National university of Colombia. Medellín Colombia.

Mobile: (+57)3003022789 Email: cjvargasc@gmail.com

**Sebastián López Cardona.** (Systems and Software engineer)

MCI Developer at Chef Inc. Medellín Colombia.

Mobile: (+57)3016447012

Email: lopezcardona24@gmail.com